Preliminary Guide to the Third Side Press Records, 1991-2003 RL.01287
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Third Side Press records
1991-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Third Side Press
RL.01287
13.2 Linear Feet
Third Side Press, a feminist publisher of women's health and lesbian fiction books, was founded in 1991 and ceased active publication in 1998. It was dissolved as a corporation in 2003. During the years of active publication, Third Side Press produced between 20 and 25 titles, mostly in paperback, including top sellers such as CANCER AS A WOMEN'S ISSUE and THE WOMAN-CENTERED ECONOMY. Midge Stocker is the founder and publisher of Third Side Press. Materials include correspondence, financial records, book proofs and files, book reviews, and other records relating to the operation of Third Side Press publishing house. Also includes copies of several Third Side Press publications. Floppy disks and other electronic materials have been removed for preservation. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
8775 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2008 (2008-0283), 13.2 lin. ft.
Historical Note
Third Side Press, a feminist publisher of women's health and lesbian fiction books, was founded in 1991 and ceased active publication in 1998. It was dissolved as a corporation in 2003. During the years of active publication, Third Side Press produced between 20 and 25 titles, mostly in paperback, including top sellers such as CANCER AS A WOMEN'S ISSUE and THE WOMAN-CENTERED ECONOMY. Midge Stocker was the founder and publisher of Third Side Press.
Collection Overview
Materials include correspondence, financial records, book proofs and files, book reviews, and other records relating to the operation of Third Side Press publishing house. Also includes copies of several Third Side Press publications. Floppy disks and other electronic materials have been removed for preservation. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Women -- Health and hygiene; Floppy disks; Proofs (printed matter); Financial records; Press releases; Reviews (document genre); Feminist theory; Cancer in women; Lesbians -- United States; Gays' writings -- United States; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Stocker, Midge, 1960-; Third Side Press; Third Side Press
- Third Side Press Records, 1991-2003, 10 boxes
  Arrangement note
  This is a preliminary finding aid created for an unprocessed collection. Materials have been reboxed, but no additional arrangement or organization has been completed at this time. Electronic materials have been withdrawn for preservation.
  - Annotated and proof copies of Third Side Press books: (Box 1)
    - Cancer as a Women's Issue (Box 1)
    - On Lill Street (Box 1)
    - She's Always Liked the Girls Best (Box 1)
    - Some Body to Love (Box 1)
  - Covers and author's proofs, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Typescripts and manuscripts:
    - Cancer as a Women's Issue (Box 1)
    - Some Body to Love (Box 1)
    - Aftershocks (Box 1)
  - Photographs and negatives (Box 1)
  - Cancer as a Women's Issue: (Box 2)
    - Author proofs (Box 2)
    - Permissions (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991-1994
    - Requests (Box 2)
    - Author (Box 2)
    - Other (Box 2)
  - Financial records, 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Financial records, 1997-2002 (Box 3)
  - Third Side Press Meadows, 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Financial records and taxes, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Taxes, 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - Alphabetical files (includes book files, subject files, and correspondence files)
    - Aftershake (Box 4)
    - Beyond Bedlam (Box 4)
    - Coming Full Circle (Box 4)
    - Copyright (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: publishers (Box 4)
  - Alphabetical files (continued) (Box 5)
    - Correspondence: readers (Box 5)
    - Correspondence: requests (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous unfoldered materials (Box 5)
    - Layout sheets (Box 5)
    - The Country of Herself (Box 5)
    - Death of a Much-Travelled Woman (Box 5)
    - Endometriosis (Box 5)
    - Entwined (Box 5)
    - ISBN (Box 5)
    - Library of Congress (Box 5)
    - Not So Much the Fall (Box 5)
    - On Lill Street (Box 5)
    - Out for Blood (Box 5)
    - The Sensual Thread (Box 5)
    - She's Always Liked the Girls Best (Box 5)
    - Some Body to Love (Box 5)
    - Speaking in Whispers (Box 5)
    - Timber City Masks (Box 5)
  - Monthly consortium sales and distribution figures, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Monthly consortium sales and distribution figures, 2001-2002 (Box 6)
  - Royalty statements, 1995-2004 (Box 6)
  - Tax and bank documents, 1991-2003 (Box 6)
  - Book distributor files, 1992-1995 (Box 6)
  - Book distributor files, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
  - Women-Centered Economy (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous ads and reviews (Box 7)
  - Ads and Reviews (Box 8)
    - Aftershocks (Box 8)
    - Alternatives for Women with Endometriosis (Box 8)
    - Beyond Bedlam (Box 8)
    - Cancer/1 (Box 8)
    - Cancer/2 (Box 8)
    - Coming Full Circle (Box 8)
    - The Country of Herself (Box 8)
    - Crystal Mountain Veils (Box 8)
    - Death of a Much-Travelled Woman (Box 8)
    - Entwined (Box 8)
    - Hawkings (Box 8)
    - On Lill Street (Box 8)
    - Mayor of Heaven (Box 8)
    - Not So Much the Fall (Box 8)
    - Out for Blood (Box 8)
    - Out for More Blood (Box 8)
    - The Sensual Thread (Box 8)
    - She's Always Liked the Girls Best (Box 8)
    - Some Body to Love (Box 8)
    - Speaking in Whispers (Box 8)
    - Timber City Masks (Box 8)
    - The Woman-Centered Economy (Box 8)
  - Author and other photographs (Box 8)
  - Administrative files, 1991-2000 (Box 8)
  - Consortium files (Box 8)
  - Customer correspondence (Box 8)
  - Office Depot (Box 8)
  - Orders (Box 8)
  - Sales reports (Box 9)
  - Actual printers (Box 9)
  - Cranes (Box 9)
  - Don Reed Bookbinding (Box 9)
  - Graphic Arts Services (Box 9)
  - Infocomm (Box 9)
  - Malloy (Box 9)
  - McNaughton and Gunn (Box 9)
  - Copies of Third Side Press Books (Box 10)
    - Speaking in Whispers (2 copies) (Box 10)
    - Alternatives for Women with Endometriosis (Box 10)
    - The Death of a Much-Travelled Woman (Box 10)
    - The Woman-Centered Economy (Box 10)
    - On Lill Street (Box 10)
    - Confronting Cancer, Constructing Change (Box 10)
    - Cancer as a Women's Issue (Box 10)
    - Coming Full Circle (Box 10)
    - Out for Blood (Box 10)
    - Out for More Blood (Box 10)
    - Beyond Bedlam (Box 10)
    - Not So Much the Fall (Box 10)
    - The Mayor of Heaven (Box 10)